whitney.org 2018-04-09

# Privacy Policy | Whitney Museum of American Art

## Introduction

The Whitney Museum of American Art (also herein referred to as “WMAA” or the “Museum”) is committed to protecting the privacy of its online guests, customers, members, donors, and friends. We understand that maintaining privacy on the Museum’s websites (whitney.org, artport.whitney.org, library.whitney.org, shopwhitney.org, and exhibition-specific websites, herein referred to as “the Website” or “the Site”) is very important, and that informing our visitors about the types of information we collect and how we use it is crucial to the Museum’s mission.

## Acceptance of Terms

By using any of the Museum website(s), you signify your acceptance without limitation or qualification of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use the Website.

Please note that the Museum may revise this Privacy Policy at any time, without notice. Any such change is effective immediately upon posting it on the Website. Such revisions may arise in response to changes in the law, policy, or other factors. You agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy and any modifications to this Privacy Policy occurring prior to your continued use of the Website, visiting the Museum or attending events to which you may have purchased tickets. We encourage you to periodically visit this page to review our most current policy. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to these terms will indicate your acceptance of those changes.

Certain provisions of this Privacy Policy may be superseded by expressly designated legal notices or terms located on particular pages on the Website. 

## Types of Information Collected

The Museum does not collect any personal information about individuals, such as names, contact information (including postal or email addresses), or other personally identifying data (the “Personal Information”) except when such information is knowingly provided. Personal information might be obtained from online transactions such as purchases, subscriptions, registrations, or membership pledges. Additionally, personal information may be transmitted as part of a form submission or in connection with other activities, services, or resources available on our website.

 **Information Provided by Visitors**

 _Online Mailing Lists_  
When you subscribe to our Online mailing list(s), the Whitney will request information necessary to process your subscription and send you the information you seek: your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, and areas of interest. Your Personal Information may be used as set forth below.

 _Online Store Purchases and Purchases of Memberships_  
When you purchase a Whitney Museum membership or an item from the Museum store online, the Whitney and its third party merchants and agents will request information necessary to process your purchase or process your membership and acknowledge your contribution: your name, billing and shipping address, telephone number, e-mail address and credit card information. Your credit card information will be used only for the purpose of processing and documenting the transaction. Your Personal Information may be used as set forth below.

 _Online Admissions and Program and Event Tickets_  
When you purchase online tickets through the site (including tickets for admission to the Whitney Museum, special exhibitions, special events, performances, lectures, and other educational programs offered by the Whitney), the Whitney and its third party merchants and agents will request information necessary to process your order: your name, billing and shipping address, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. Your credit card information will be used only for the purpose of processing and documenting the transaction. Your Personal Information may be used as set forth below.

 **Information Collected Automatically**

 _Non-Personal Information_  
The Museum does automatically collect some anonymous “non-personally identifiable” aggregate information about visitors when pages are requested through a browser. This information is used for statistical purposes, to help us monitor how guests navigate our site, allowing us to tailor our services for specific groups of visitors. Non-personally identifiable information may refer to information about our visitors’ browsers (e.g., Google Chrome, Safari or Internet Explorer), operating systems (e.g., Windows or Macintosh), Internet Service Providers (e.g., Time Warner Cable, Verizon, AOL, Earthlink, etc.), and other similar information.

 _Aggregate Information  _  
The Museum collects IP addresses as a component of the non-personally identifiable aggregate information. An IP address is a number assigned to your computer by a web server when you’re on the Internet. This information is used only for non-user-specific purposes such as determining how many users visited a specific area of our site. Such information could, if necessary, also be used to identify a user in order to comply with safety and/or security issues or with legal requirements, but only in extraordinary circumstances.

 _Cookies  and Web Beacons_  
A cookie is a small text file that is sent to your browser from a website and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies can’t read data from your hard drive or read cookie files that were created by other sites—the website that creates a cookie is the only one a browser will permit to access it. Examples of ways in which the Museum might use are to control access to certain user features, to customize content areas, and to analyze site activity and user behavior. The Museum also reserves the right to use cookies in the future in conjunction with new content or extended functionality.

If you are concerned about the use of cookies, the Museum suggests that you explore your browser’s options to notify you whenever a cookie is set, or to disallow cookies altogether. Users should be aware, however, that prohibiting the use of cookies may restrict the user’s access to certain types of content or features. Numerous online resources explain cookies and describe how to disable them (for example, the [Federal Reserve of New York](http://www.ny.frb.org/cookies.html)).

We also allow third-party companies to collect certain non-personally identifiable information (e.g., the type of browser and/or operating system you use, time and date, and information relating to the content you are viewing) on our behalf when you visit our digital properties.  These companies may use such non-personally identifiable information in order to provide advertisements about our exhibits, events, programs, goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you on other digital properties.  These companies typically use a cookie, a web beacon or other technology to collect this information.  To learn more about this targeted advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising via cookies, you can visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> if located in the United States or Canada or <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/> if located in Europe.

## How Information is Used

Any Personal Information provided to the Museum is maintained and accessible only by the Museum and will not be made available to third parties except as permitted by the Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy.

 **Marketing and Promotion  
** If you provide us with your email address, this will be deemed permission for us to email you information about our exhibition, events, and other programs and activities, as well as for any marketing or promotional purposes. However, you may withdraw this permission using our opt-out procedure. You will not receive such communications unless you have knowingly provided the Personal Information required. In some cases, you will be required to opt-in by joining a newsgroup or mailing list. If you do opt-in, you will always have the option to opt-out at any time by unsubscribing to that particular list or following the opt-out instructions included within the body of the email message.

 **Membership  **  
If you sign up for a membership online, your Personal Information will be entered into the Museum’s membership database. We may share your Personal Information with other reputable organizations, such as other nonprofits, art institutions and companies. If you do not want to have your information used in this way, you may send an e-mail message containing your name and postal address to [memberinfo@whitney.org](mailto:memberinfo@whitney.org). We may also share such information with third-party vendors who help us analyze and understand our donor and membership base.

 **Use of Outside Vendors  
** The Museum may from time to time retain qualified third-party vendors in order to help us manage the Museum Web Site and allow us to better serve our visitors and customers. These may include third-party vendors we engage to analyze the information we collect on the Museum Web Site. The Museum requires its vendors to maintain the security of the Personal Information to which they are provided access and restricts third-party vendors from using Personal Information in any way not expressly authorized by Museum.

We may contract with third parties who use Cookies to collect information on our behalf. These parties are required to maintain the confidentiality of this information. We may contract with companies or others to provide certain services, including credit card processing, Information management, promotional services, etc. We provide these service providers with the information they need to perform these services, but we restrict them from using the information in any way not expressly authorized by Museum.

 **Opt-Out  **  
If for any reason you do not wish to receive further email from the Museum, please follow the instructions for unsubscribing included within the body of the message that was sent to you, or e-mail a message containing your name and address to [memberinfo@whitney.org](mailto:memberinfo@whitney.org).

## With Whom Information is Shared

The Museum may share your Personal Information, as collected under the circumstances outlined above, with other reputable organizations, such as other non-profits, art institutions, or companies.  The Museum has teamed up with reputable third-party vendors in order to provide certain services to its online users as described above.

## Security

The Museum protects all personal and non-personally identifiable information that it receives via the Internet against unauthorized access. In addition, the Museum’s website uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption to process purchases made through its online store and ticketing systems. By using this technology, online customers can be confident that their personal information is protected from interception by any third party. Sensitive credit card information is not permanently stored on any WMAA web server and, though your order information is retained for our records, this information is never shared with other companies or persons.

What is a secure connection? When a secure connection is established between your browser and a website, any data that is transferred over the connection is encrypted to prevent it from being viewed by a third party. Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption, the standard for most browsers and servers, makes it very difficult for anyone to intercept or decode messages exchanged over this type of secure connection.  Browsers such as Google Chrome, Safari, Firefox and Internet Explorer display an image of a locked padlock in their status bar when connected to a secure site. Secure transactions are also indicated when the prefix in the location bar of your browser switches from http:// to https://. If you do not see the padlock at the bottom of your browser’s window, if the padlock is unlocked, or if the protocol in the location bar is not listed as https://, then any data exchanged with the website is potentially visible to others. Depending on your browser, you may be able to view authentication information about a secure page by double-clicking on the locked padlock in the status bar. For more information on how your software establishes a secure connection, see the help files for your particular browser.

## Links to Other Sites

Users may find content on the Museum’s site that links to the sites and services of our partners, sponsors, or other third parties. In many cases, these links represent cooperative projects or are established with persons or entities that have a significant connection to or relationship with our site. Although every effort is made to ensure that any referrals are to reputable and relevant sources, the Museum does not control the content or links that appear on these sites. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies, or no policy at all. The Museum maintains a policy against the nonconsensual collection or sharing of Personal Information and encourages visitors to review the privacy policies of any sites they visit to ensure their Personal Information is being protected.

## Children

The Museum does not knowingly collect personal information from children under thirteen years of age. Children should always ask parents/ guardians for permission before providing personal information to any website or purchasing any products or services online. The WMAA urges all parents/ guardians to participate in their children’s exploration of the Internet and to teach them about protecting their personal information while online.

## Policy Changes

Occasional changes may be made to this document as new services and content are added to our site or to reflect changes in the Museum’s policies. Visitors to the Museum’s website are encouraged to check this document periodically to stay informed of current Museum privacy guidelines.

Last updated July 21, 2016
